Register of the Kurt Richard Grossmann Papers, 1913-1973
Hoover Institution Archives
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, c.1933-1972 (Box 16-36)
  - "Gibt es noch Wiedergutmachungsprobleme? Unterhaltung mit Martin Hirsch in Bonn," (Are there still restitution problems, conversation with M.H. in Bonn) Aufbau, Printed copy., September 1967. (Reel 32, Folder 25: 40)
  - "Grenzen der Wiedergutmachung," (Limits of restitution), Aufbau, Printed copies., January 27, 1967. (Folder 25: 41, Reel 32)
  - "Der Grosse Bruder wacht," (Big Brother is watching), Tagwacht, Typescript and printed copy., February 16, 1971. (Folder 26: 1, Reel 32)
  - "Ein grosser Friedenskaempfer--Zum Tode von Hein Herbers," (A great champion of peace--On the death of H.H.), Aufbau, Typescript and printed copy., September 13, 1968. (Folder 26: 2, Reel 32)
  - "Ein grosser Zeichner, zum Tode Julius Krolls," (A great artist, on the death of J.K.), Aufbau, Printed copy., June 14, 1968. (Folder 26: 3, Reel 32)
  - "Die groessere Gefahr kommt von innen..." (The greater danger comes from within), Jedioth Chadashoth, Typescript and printed copy., January 16, 1970. (Folder 26: 4, Reel 32)
  - "Gruss an Armin T. Wegner," (Greetings to A.T.W.), Aufbau, Typescript and printed copy., May 10, 1968. (Folder 26: 5, Reel 32)
  - "Die gute Erde und der gesunde Menschenverstand," (The good earth and healthy reason), Tagwacht, Typescript and printed copies., May 8, 1970. (Reel 32, Folder 26: 6)
  - "Hakenkreuze," (Swastikas), Aufbau, Printed copy., August 21, 1942. (Reel 32, Folder 26: 7)
  - "Halbzeit 1969: Nixon als Buergerpraesident," (Halfway, through 1969: N. as citizen president), Jedioth Chadashoth, Printed copies., August 8, 1969. (Folder 26: 8, Reel 32)
  - "Hans Staudinger--Der Mann und der Mensch," (H.S.--The man and the human being), Typescript (carbon copies). (Folder 26: 9, Reel 32)
  - "Hartwig Eberhard Helmrich--ein Unbesungener Held," (H.E.H.--an unsung hero), Jedioth Chadashoth, Printed copy., August 22, 1969. (Folder 26: 10, Reel 32)
  - "Hartwig Eberhard Helmrich gestorben," (H.E.H. died), Aufbau, Printed copy., May 16, 1969. (Folder 26: 11, Reel 32)
  - "Hass und Furcht siegten," (Hate and fear won), Tagwacht, Printed copy., June 2, 1969. (Folder 26: 12, Reel 33)
  - "Hat John V. Lindsay eine Chance?" Jedioth Chadashoth, Printed copy., September 10, 1971. (Folder 26: 13, Reel 33)
  - "Hat man in Prag Muenchen vergessen?" (Have those in Prague forgotten Munich?), Aufbau, Printed copy., August 4, 1967. (Reel 33, Folder 26: 14)
  - "Hat Nixon schon gewonnen?" (Has N. already won?), Tagwacht, Printed copy., September 21, 1968. (Folder 26: 15, Reel 33)
  - "Hat Ted Kennedy noch eine Chance?" Jedioth Chadashoth, Printed copy., January 23, 1970. (Reel 33, Folder 26: 16)
  - "Das Haus zu Ehren Einsteins," (The house in honor of E.), Aufbau, Printed copy, December 26, 1969. (Folder 26: 17, Reel 33)
  - "Have the Germans Paid Their Debt to the Jews?" Congress Bulletin, Printed copy., September 1961. (Reel 33, Folder 26: 18)
  - "Heinz Kurt Fabian, 60 Jahre," Aufbau, Printed copy., May 19, 1967. (Folder 26: 19, Reel 33)
  - "Das heisse Eisen der Verjaehrungsfrist von New York aus-gesehen," (The tricky question of the German statute of limitations as seen from New York), Typescript (carbon copy). (Reel 33, Folder 26: 20)
  - "Heldinnen der Emigration," (heroines of the emigration), Die Frau in der Gemeinschaft, Typescript and printed copies., June-July 1963. (Reel 33, Folder 26: 21)
  - "Helene Stoecker," Aufbau, Printed copy., March 5, 1943. (Reel 33, Folder 26: 22)
  - "Helfer in der Not, Friedrich Bill 60 Jahre," (Helper in adversity, F.B. 60 years old), Aufbau, Printed copy., January 2, 1954. (Reel 33, Folder 26: 23)
  - "Henri Dunant--Der Vater des Roten Kreuzes," (H.D.--Father of the Red Cross), Typescript., n.d. (Reel 33, Folder 26: 24)
  - "Herbert S. Schoenfeldt," Aufbau Mimeographed copy., July 7, 1956. (Reel 33, Folder 26: 25)
  - "Hildegurd knickste und verteidigte die Jugend," (H. curtsied and defended the young people), Koelner Stadt Anzeiger, Printed copy., December 30, 1960. (Folder 26: 26, Reel 33)
  - "A History of Austrian Restitution," by G. Jellinek, translated into English and edited by Grossmann, Typescript (carbon copies). (Folder 26: 27, Reel 33)
  - "A History of Zionism in Germany," Encyclopedia of Zionism and Israel, Typescript (carbon copy) and related material., 1964. (Reel 33, Folder 26: 28)
  - "Hitler's Greatest Moral Defeat," Typescript (carbon copies)., 1963. (Folder 26: 29, Reel 33)
  - "Hoch klingt das Lied vom braven Mann. Eberhard Helmrichs Alleinkampf gegen den Naziterror," (The resounding song of a stalward man. E.H.'s solitary battle against Nazi terror), Aufbau, Printed copy., August 23, 1968. (Folder 26: 30, Reel 33)
  - "Hoffnung auf die Jugend, Entspannung, Friedenssicherung, und Wiedergutmachung," (Hope for youth, detente, peace, and restitution), Typescript (carbon copy). (Folder 26: 31, Reel 33)
  - "Eine Hoffnung fuer den Sueden," (Hope for the South), Tagwacht, Printed copy., March 22, 1971. (Folder 26: 32, Reel 33)
  - "Hoffnungen, die sich nicht erfuellten," (Hopes that were not fulfilled), Mimeographed copy., July 16, 1954. (Reel 33, Folder 26: 33)
  - "Hoffnungen und Befuerchtungen--Washington," (Hopes and fears--Washington), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., October 23, 1969. (Folder 26: 34, Reel 33)
  - "Human Beings Between the Boundaries," Typescript (carbon copy). (Folder 26: 35, Reel 33)
  - "The Humanitarian who Cheated Hitler," Coronet, Printed copy., September 1959. (Folder 26: 36, Reel 33)
  - "Humphreys misslungener Versuch," (H.'s unsuccessful attempt), Tagwacht, Printed copy., October 5, 1968. (Folder 26: 37, Reel 33)
  - "Hunger in den USA," Tagwacht, Printed copy., March 17, 1969. (Reel 33, Folder 26: 38)
  - "Die Huete fliegen in den Ring," (Hats fly in the ring), Jedioth Chadashoth, Typescript and printed copy., January 14, 1972. (Reel 33, Folder 26: 39)
  - "Ich sage vor keinem deutschen Gericht mehr aus--Norbert Wollheim der voreingenommene Zeuge," (I will not testify before another German court--N.W. the hostile witness), Aufbau, Printed copy., December 16, 1966. (Reel 33, Folder 26: 40)
  - "Ihre Aera ist zu Ende--Die Geschichte wird ueber die Leistung von Johnson und Rusk entscheiden," (Their era has come to an end history will judge the performance of J. and R.), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., January 23, 1969. (Reel 33, Folder 26: 41)
  - "Illusionen: Das Land verlaesst die Regierung," (Illusions: The country is abandoning the goverment), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., February 15, 1968. (Reel 33, Folder 26: 42)
  - "Illusionen ueber das Halt der Endloesung," (Illusions about the end of the final solution), Aufbau, November 11, 1966. (Reel 33, Folder 26: 43)
  - "Im Bett erschossen--Sind die Black Panthers eine Staatsgefahr," (Shot in bed--Are the B.P. a threat to the state), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., January 15, 1970. (Folder 26: 44, Reel 33)
  - "Im Hintergrund Rockefeller--Das Panorama des Wahl kampfes wird bunter," (Rockefeller in the background, panorama of the election campaign becomes more colorful), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., April 25, 1968. (Folder 26: 45, Reel 33)
  - "Im Vorfeld der Novemberwahlen 1970," (In the forefront of the November elections 1970), Typescript (carbon copy)., June 1970. (Folder 26: 46, Reel 33)
  - "Immer wieder: Die Gesundheitsschaeden," (Once again: health damages), Aufbau, Printed copy., November 10, 1961. (Folder 26: 47, Reel 33)
  - "Immigration und Arbeitslosigkeit," (Immigration and unemployment), Aufbau, Printed copy., May 17, 1940. (Folder 26: 48, Reel 33)
  - "In den USA steigt die nationalistische Welle," (In the US there is a rising tide of nationalism), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., February 29, 1968. (Folder 26: 49, Reel 33)
  - "In der Stunde der Dunkelheit--Papst Pius XII, die Juden und Hitler," (In the hour of darkness--Pope Pius XII, the Jews and Hitler), Rheinischer Merkur, Printed copy., October 31, 1958. (Reel 33, Folder 26: 50)
  - "In falscher Richtung," (In the wrong direction), Israelitisches Wochenblatt, Printed copy., February 19, 1960. (Reel 33, Folder 26: 51)
  - "In letzter Minute, die Fluechtlings konferenz in Washington," (At the last minute, the refugee conference in W.), Aufbau, Printed copy., n.d. (Reel 33, Folder 26: 52)
  - "Individual Claims Against Germany," Mimeographed copy. (Reel 33, Folder 26: 53)
  - "International Solidaritaet--statt Auslandshilfe," (International solidarity instead of foreign aid), Boletin informativo, Typescript and printed copy. (Reel 33, Folder 26: 54)
  - "Ist das Entschaedi gungswerk nun am Ende?" (Is the restitution work now at an end?), Jedioth Chadashoth, Printed copy., May 23, 1971. (Reel 33, Folder 26: 55)
  - "Ist der Kennedy-Mythos zu Ende?" (Is the Kennedy myth over?), Tagwacht, Printed copies., July 13, 1970. (Reel 33, Folder 26: 56)
  - "Ist der Rechtsextremismus in Deutschland eine neue Gefahr?" (Is right wing extremism a new danger in Germany?), Typescript (carbon copy) and related material. (Reel 33, Folder 26: 57)
  - "Ist die materielle Wiedergutmachung beendet?" (Has material restitution come to an end?). Frankfurter Hefte, Printed copy., February 1968. (Reel 33, Folder 26: 58)
  - "Ist eine General-Amnestie fuer NS-Verbrecher vertretbar?" (Is general amnesty for Nazi criminals justifiable?), Vorgaenge, Printed copy., July 1964. (Reel 33, Folder 26: 59)
  - "Ist Richard Nixon seines Sieges im November sicher?" (Is R.N. certain of victory in November?), Jedioth Chadashoth, Typescript and printed copy., January 28, 1972. (Folder 26: 60, Reel 33)
  - "Jackies Zeilenhandel--Streit um den Tod eines Praesidenten," (J's dealing in publishing, controversy about the book Death of a President), Vorwaerts, February 2, 1967. (Folder 26: 61, Reel 33)
  - "Die Jahreswende 1971-1972," (The new year), Typescript (carbon copy)., December 21, 1971. (Folder 26: 62, Reel 33)
  - "Jahreswende--Schicksalswende?" (New year--new course?), Boletin Informative, Printed copy., February 1968. (Folder 26: 63, Reel 33)
  - "Das Jahrhundert der Entwurzelten," (The century of the uprooted), Die neue Zeitung, Printed copies and related material., April 17, 1951. (Folder 26: 64, Reel 34)
  - "The Jewish Community in Berlin--November 1961," Mimeographed copy., December 1961. (Folder 26: 65, Reel 34)
  - The Jewish DP Problem. Reviews and related material, Typescripts and printed copies., 1951. (Reel 34, Folder 27: 1)
  - "Jewish Migration Today," Jewish Spectator, November 1949. (Folder 27: 2, Reel 34)
  - The Jewish Refugee, by Arieh Tartakower and Kurt R. Grossmann. New York: Institute of Jewish Affairs, Printed copy., 1944. (Folder 27: 3, Reel 34)
  - "Jews and Germany, 1964," Herzl Institute Bulletin, Printed copy., November 22, 1964. (Folder 27: 4, Reel 35)
  - "Jews in Danger Zones," S.A. Jewish Times, Mimeographed and printed copies., March 11, 1949. (Reel 35, Folder 27: 5)
  - "Johnson sucht einen Ausweg fuer Nahost," (J. seeks a way out for the Near East), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., November 9, 1967. (Reel 35, Folder 27: 6)
  - "Johnson's Faust im Pentagon--Clark Clifford hat Verdienste als Wahlmanager und Falke," (J.'s fist in the Pentagon--C.C.'s services as campaign manager and 'hawk'), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., February 1, 1968. (Reel 35, Folder 27: 7)
  - "Johnson's Sorgen: Die Roosevelt Allianz loest sich langsam auf," (J's worry: the Roosevelt alliance is slowly dissolving), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., April 20, 1967. (Folder 27: 8, Reel 35)
  - "Die Juden in der Sowjetunion," (Jews in the Soviet Union) Typescript (carbon copy). (Reel 35, Folder 27: 9)
  - "Die Juden in Deutschland jetzt," (Jews in Germany today), Aufbau, Printed copy., August 8, 1969. (Folder 27: 10, Reel 35)
  - "Juden und Judentum in den Vereinigten Staaten," (Jews and Jewry in the US), Typescript and related material., 1971. (Folder 27: 11, Reel 35)
  - Die Judenfeindschaft, (Antisemitism), Reviews. Printed copies., 1963. (Folder 27: 12, Reel 35)
  - "Judenverfolgung in Italien," (Persecution of the Jews in Italy), Aufbau, Printed copy., July 6, 1962. (Folder 27: 13, Reel 35)
  - "Judicial Evasions of the Peace Treaty, 1918-1932," South Atlantic Quarterly, Printed copy., January 1944. (Folder 27: 14, Reel 35)
  - "Die jüdischen Auslandsorganisationen und ihre Arbeit in Deutschland" (Jewish foreign organizations and their work in Germany), Printed copies. (Folder 27: 15, Reel 35)
  - "Juedischer Weltkongress," (Jewish World Congress), Typescript (carbon copy)., n.d. (Folder 27: 16, Reel 35)
  - "Der Junker, der von Rechts kam und nach Links ging," (The aristocrat who came from the right and went to the left), Typescript (carbon copy)., 1966. (Reel 35, Folder 27: 17)
  - "Justiz im Zwielicht," (Justice in twilight), Aufbau, Printed copy., May 8, 1964. (Reel 35, Folder 27: 18)
  - "Der Justiz steht vor Gericht," (Justice stands before the court), Jedioth Chadashoth, Typescript and printed copies., March 26, 1971. (Reel 35, Folder 27: 19)
  - "Justizfaelle, die nicht sterben: der Lindbergh Fall," (Legal cases that do not die: the Lindbergh case), Typescript (carbon copies). (Reel 35, Folder 27: 20)
  - "Justizminister und Verfassung," (The Secretary of Justice and the constitution), Tagwacht, Printed copy., July 12, 1971. (Reel 35, Folder 27: 21)
  - "Der Kampf um die Rententabellen," (The battle over the pension tables), Aufbau, Printed copy., October 27, 1967. (Reel 35, Folder 27: 22)
  - "Der Kampf ums Recht ist niht beendet," (The battle for justice is not over), Typescript (carbon copy)., November 11, 1967. (Reel 35, Folder 27: 23)
  - "Ein Kaempfer fuer die Freiheit," (A fighter for freedom), Aufbau, Printed copy., June 21, 1963. (Reel 35, Folder 27: 24)
  - "Kaempfer gegen die Kraefte des Boesen, Gerhart H. Seger wurde 70," (Fighter against the powers of evil, G.H.S. at 70.) Berliner Stimme, November 19, 1966. (Folder 27: 25, Reel 35)
  - "Kann der Senat den Vietnamkrieg beenden?" (Can the Senate end the war in Viet Nam?), Typescript (carbon copy). (Folder 27: 26, Reel 35)
  - "Die katholische Verschwoerung an der Ostkueste," (The Catholic conspiracy on the East Coast), Jedioth Chadashoth, Typescript and printed copy., February 12, 1971. (Folder 27: 27, Reel 35)
  - "Kein glueckliches Jahr fuer Fortschrittliche," (Not a good year for progressives), Tagwacht, Printed copy., August 1, 1969. (Folder 27: 28, Reel 35)
  - "Kein gutes Omen fuer Entspannung," (Not a good omen for detente), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., December 12, 1968. (Folder 27: 29, Reel 35)
  - "Kein juedischer Widerstand im Dritten Reich?" (No Jewish resistance in the Third Reich?), Rheinischer Merkur, Printed copy., July 19, 1963. (Reel 35, Folder 28: 1)
  - "Kein Witz mehr," (No longer a joke), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., April, 13, 1967. (Reel 35, Folder 28: 2)
  - "Keine Deutschenhetze in den USA," (No anti-German campaign in the US), Die Welt, Printed copies., March 31, 1962. (Reel 35, Folder 28: 3)
  - "Keine Hilfe fuer die Helfer," (No help for the helpers," Sueddeutsche Zeitung, Printed copy., November 14, 1962. (Reel 35, Folder 28: 4)
  - "Keine Vergeltung--aber Gerechtigkeit," (No reward--but justice), Das feie Wort Printed copy., September 28, 1951. (Reel 35, Folder 28: 5)
  - "Kempner gegen Quick," (Kempner vs. Quick), Typescript (carbon copy) and related material. (Reel 35, Folder 28: 6)
  - "Kennedy und Israel," Typescript (carbon copy). (Reel 35, Folder 28: 7)
  - "Kinder- und Jugendjahre," (Childhood and early years), birthday tribute to Robert Sommer, Typescript and carbon copy. (Folder 28: 8, Reel 35)
  - "Klaerung in Algerien," (Clarification in Algeria), Aufbau, Printed copy., October 29, 1943. (Reel 35, Folder 28: 9)
  - "Ein kleiner Krieg ist angeklagt, Prozess gegen einen Kinderarzt auf dem Hintergrund Vietnams," (A little war is declared, trial against a pediatrician against the background of Viet Nam," Vorwaerts, Printed copy., January 18, 1968. (Reel 35, Folder 28: 10)
  - "Kommen wir um den dritten Weltkrieg herum?" (Are we avoiding the Third World War?), Jedioth Chadashoth, Typescript and printed copies., September 27, 1971. (Reel 35, Folder 28: 11)
  - "Konfrontation im Nahen Osten," (Confrontation in the Near East), Tagwacht, Printed copy., September 28, 1970. (Reel 35, Folder 28: 12)
  - "Kongress-Halbzeit und der Praesident," (Congress at half time and the President), Typescript (carbon copy). (Reel 35, Folder 28: 13)
  - "Koennen wir--ja duerfen wir verzeihen? Anmerkung zu Simon Wiesenthals neuem Buch Die Sonnenblume," (Can we--or may we forgive? Comment on S.W.'s new book Die Sonnenblume) Typescript (carbon copy)., n.d. (Reel 35, Folder 28: 14)
  - "Konrad Adenauer und die Wiedergutmachung," (K.A. and restitution), Aufbau, Printed copy., May 5, 1967. (Folder 28: 15, Reel 35)
  - "Die Kontakte des Pentagon," Jedioth Chadashoth, Printed copy., August 6, 1969. (Folder 28: 16, Reel 35)
  - "Koepfe zu aktuellen USA Probleme," (Comments on current US problems), Tagwacht, Printed copy., August 25, 1969. (Folder 28: 17, Reel 35)
  - "Die Korrektur der Entschaedigungs-Rententabellen," Typescript (carbon copy)., September 1970. (Folder 28: 18, Reel 35)
  - "Korrumpiertes Establishment," Tagwacht, Printed copy., November 26, 1970. (Reel 35, Folder 28: 19)
  - "Krankheit--ein Luxus in USA," (Illness--a luxury in the US), Jedioth Chadashoth, Printed copy., August 10, 1969. (Folder 28: 20, Reel 35)
  - "Die Krankheiten der amerikanischen Gesellschaft," (Sicknesses of American society), Jedioth Chadashoth, Printed copy., May 2, 1969. (Reel 36, Folder 28: 21)
  - "Krieg in Vietnam und Gesetz," (War in Viet Nam and the law), Tagwacht, Printed copy., April 11, 1970. (Reel 36, Folder 28: 22)
  - "Krieg mit anderen Mitteln--Ammerkungen zum bevorstehenden China-Besuch Nixons," (War with other means--Comments on Nixon's coming visit to China), Tagwacht, Printed copy., July 1971. (Folder 28: 23, Reel 36)
  - "Krise der Wiedergutmachung," (Restitution crisis), Aufbau, Printed copies., November 26, 1965. (Folder 28: 24, Reel 36)
  - "Lage der Emigranten in Frankreich," (Situation of emigres in France), Printed copy., November 15, 1939. (Folder 28: 25, Reel 36)
  - "Die Lage des Praesidenten--Lyndon B. Johnsons Botschaft ueber die Lage der Nation," (The state of the President--L.B.J.'s report on the state of the nation), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., January 25, 1968. (Folder 28: 26, Reel 36)
  - "Die Laos Invasion erzeugt keine heftige Opposition," (The invasion of Laos has not evoked any strong opposition), Typescript (carbon copy)., n.d. (Folder 28: 27, Reel 36)
  - "Der Laeufer mit der Fackel--Zum 25. Todestag von Carl von Ossietzky," (The runner with the torch--On the 25th anniversary of the death of C. von O.), Telegraf, Typescript, mimeographed, and printed copies., May 1, 1963. (Folder 28: 28, Reel 36)
  - "L.B.J. ist keine lahme Ente," (L.B.J. is no lame duck), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., July 25, 1968. (Folder 28: 29, Reel 36)
  - "L.B. Johnson nahm Abschied," (L.B.J. took his leave), Tagwacht, Printed copy., January 20, 1969. (Reel 36, Folder 28: 30)
  - "Ein Leben im Kampfe fuer Gerechtigkeit," (A life in battle for justice), outline, Typescript (carbon copy)., n.d. (Reel 36, Folder 28: 31)
  - "Das Leben--kein Traum," (Life--not a dream), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., September 3, 1970. (Reel 36, Folder 28: 32)
  - "Lehren aus der Geschichte," (Lessons from history), Telegraf, Printed copy., April 1966. (Reel 36, Folder 28: 33)
  - "A Letter from Czechoslovakia," Herzl Institute Bulletin, Printed copies., January 14, 1968. (Reel 36, Folder 28: 34)
  - "Letter from Czechoslovakia: Revisit after thirty years," Typescript (carbon copy)., n.d. (Reel 36, Folder 28: 35)
  - Letter to the editor, The Times, re Germans in Czechoslovakia. Printed copy., December 1937 (Folder 28: 36, Reel 36)
  - Letter to the editor, Aufbau, re sending food to Europe. Printed copy., June 11, 1943 (Folder 28: 37, Reel 36)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times, re anti-semitism in Germany. Printed copies., February 13, 1959 (Folder 28: 38, Reel 36)
  - Letter to the editor, Aufbau, re restitution. Printed copy., September 29, 1961 (Folder 28: 39, Reel 36)
  - Letter to the editor, Die Welt, re restitution. Printed copy., February 11, 1963 (Reel 36, Folder 28: 40)
  - Letter to the editor, Der Spiegel, re restitution. Printed copy., August 3, 1964 (Reel 36, Folder 28: 42)
    - Letter to the editor, Die Zeit, re restitution. Printed, March 4, 1964 (Folder 28: 41, Reel 36)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times, re Kurt Georg Kiesinger. Printed copy., November 17, 1966 (Reel 36, Folder 28: 43)
  - Letter to the editor, Vorwaerts, re student unrest. Printed copy., March 7, 1968 (Folder 28: 44)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times, re Polish-German agreement. Printed copy., January 8, 1971 (Folder 28: 45)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times, re Ilse Koch. Printed copy., May 17, 1971 (Folder 28: 46)
  - Letter to the editor, Herald Tribune, re Washington and Weimar. Printed copies., June 22, 1971 (Folder 28: 47)
  - Letter to the editor, Die Welt, re war crimes. Printed copy., November 7, 1971 (Folder 28: 48)
  - Letter to the editor, Frankfurter Allgemeine, re Ossietzky. Printed copy., December 16, 1971 (Folder 28: 49)
  - "Das letzte Kapitel der Wiedergutmachung," (The last chapter of restitution), Aufbau, Printed copy., June 4, 1965. (Folder 28: 50)
  - "Die letzte Phase" (The lust phase) in Judenfeindschaft, Karl Thieme et al, Typescript drafts and galley proof, 1963. (Folder 28: 51)
  - "Die letzte Phase der Entschaedigung," (The last phase of restitution), Aufbau, Printed copy., January 10, 1969. (Folder 28: 52)
  - "Die letzte Phase der Wiedergutmchungserkes," (The last phase of restitution work), Mimeographed copies., July 1965. (Folder 28: 53)
  - "Die letzten 17 Monate: Ein umfassender Bericht des American Joint Distribution Committee," (The last 17 months: A comprehensive report of the A.J.D.), Aufbau, Printed copy., August 21, 1942. (Folder 28: 54)
  - "Leutnant William B. Calley nur ein Suendenbock? (My Lai und das Gewissen der USA," (W.B.C. just a scapegoat? M.L. and the conscience of the US), Jedioth Chadashoth, Typescript and printed copy., April 9, 1971. (Folder 28: 55)
  - "Liberale Hoffnungen," (Liberal hopes), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., July 4, 1968. (Folder 28: 56)
  - "Die Liberalen zersplittert, die Konservativen werden staerker, ein strenger Praesident," (The liberals are divided, the conservatives are becoming stronger, a strict president), Typescript (carbon copy)., n.d. (Folder 28: 57)
  - "Ludwig Erhard zur vergangenen Barbarei," (L.E. on past barbarism), Aufbau, Printed copy., December 27, 1963. (Folder 28: 58)
  - "Lyndon und der junge Mann, Praesident Johnson wehrt sich gegen einen Kennedy," (L. and the young man, President Johnson defends himself against a Kennedy), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., March 23, 1967. (Folder 28: 59)
  - "M.G.: Kaempfer in der politischen Arena," (M.G.: Fighter in the political arena), Aufbau, Printed copy., January 7, 1966. (Folder 28: 60)
  - "Macht und Geist," (Power and intellect), Deutsche Studien, Reprint. (Folder 28: 61)
  - "Maine: das andere Amerika," Jedioth Chadashoth, September 21, 1969. (Folder 28: 62)
  - "Malaise in den USA," Jedioth Chadashoth, Typescript and printed copy., January 2, 1970. (Folder 28: 63)
  - "Der Mann, der den Hass durchkreuzte: Propst Heinrich Grueber ist in New York," (The man who crossed out hate: Pastor H.G. in N.Y.) Aufbau, Printed copy., October 5, 1962. (Folder 28: 64)
  - "Der Mann, der zu lange blieb, die turbulente Kontroverse um die FBI," (The man who stayed too long, the turbulent controversy surrounding the FBI), Tagwacht, Typescript and printed copy., April 29, 1971. (Folder 28: 65)
  - "Ein Mann Ohnegleichen," (A man without equal) Vorwaerts, Printed copy., May 20, 1971. (Folder 28: 66)